So, a Microsoft Word document would be
the most accessible option you have.
If you have to create a PDF for
some odd reason,
at least let's make sure that it's as
accessible as it can be. Okay. So, first
off, you want to make sure that you have
correct headings and and um also that
you've done used the checker and it says
that accessibility is good to go. And
once you've done all of that, then you
would click on file and then use the
export feature. And now we're going to
create a PDF. Okay. Now, this will bring
up the publish as PDF uh dialogue box
where you're going to save the uh file.
And there's an options button that you
can click on. And in here, we want to
make sure that you have create bookmarks
using headings. Okay, so that's a
separate thing in PDFs for bookmarks. We
want all the headings to be bookmarked
and we want to make sure that the
document structure tags for
accessibility is checked. And under the
PDF options, we want to have it PDF/ A
compliant. Sometimes that's PDF/UA.
All right, not optimized for image
quality, but PDFUA uh A compliant. And
hit okay. And then you hit publish.
And now you have
as an accessible PDF as you can get,
at least from the word export. There may
need to be additional um tagging that's
required to make it fully accessible,
but that's out of the scope of